TAM Yu Kit, Lester

Email: lester.tam@gmail.com

Mobile: +852 96251440

Summery

As an accomplished IT professional with more than 20 years of solid industry experience including 10 years in top tier global commercial bank. Specialized in AWS solution design & development. Processed in-depth knowledge of the full life cycle of software development (agile & waterfall) and extensive experience in global team member mentoring, building and collaboration.

Highlighted skill set/personality

- Certified scrum master.
- Certified AWS solution architect
- A leader in a small team, experience in team member mentoring, building and collaboration
- Lead and manage vendor to ensure on time delivery.
- Customer facing, good at requirement gathering & expectation management.
- Troubleshooting proficiency
- Database turning expert
- An experienced developer in Java, .net, oracle, Sybase & MSSQL
- Work with teams in different site around the world.
- Patient and diligent
- Knowledge in automation testing solution (UFT)

Professional Experience

Cathay Pacific, *March* 2016 – *Present, Solution Lead, AOC ENG (Contractor)*

- Scrum Master
 - Application modernization
 - Revamp legacy applications and migrate to AWS cloud perform
 - ◆ As a scrum master leading a scrum team
 - ◆ Build CI/CD solution in AWS cloud

Technical Exposure: AWS, Jira, Jenkins, OpenShift, Git, Node js, Java spring boot, mySql

- ➤ Lead SA in ENG major projects:
 - LAM & Ultramain re-platform
 - ◆ Leading a development team of 10 (vendor).
 - Design & setup automation testing solution by using UFT.
 - ◆ Migrate lifeblood applications to new platform.

- ◆ Complete software migration with over 500 components in a very tight timeline.
- ◆ Detail DB structure redesign.
- ◆ Leading a small testing team to complete SIT testing.
- Horizon
 - ◆ Month end process redesign and development
 - ◆ Impact analysis and remediation on existing interface and reports

Technical Exposure: AWS,.UFT, Control-M

Family business, July 2014 – Feb 2016

J.P.Morgan Chase Bank N.A., Jan 2005 - July 2014, Associate, Production support

Production support in Trade finance (2009-2014)

- ➤ Lead Support on management reporting system.
 - Managed a team of 4 to provide production support. Team members are scattered between USA, India and Hong Kong.
 - Develop guidelines and standard for the software in early design phase to ensure the software fulfill production stability standard.
 - Develop contingency and workarounds for the system.
- As a L2 production support for the trade core backend system (GTS).
 - Involved in application design phase to review and ensure new implements addressed system stability concerns.
 - Arrange, review and approve data patch execution in production environment.
 - EOD process turning to enhance system stability
 - Tuned performance to enhance system stability. e.g. Rewrite DB stored procedure, redesign table index.
 - Team representative in large scale application rollout.
 - Ad hoc report design and implementation for management level urgent needs.

Technical Exposure: J2EE, VB/C#, JSP,ASP.net, Shell script, IIS, Tomcat, Apache, Oracle, MSSQL, Sybase, MQ, SSL, autosys, Linux, unix

Application developer in Trade finance front end applications (2005-2009)

Key contributions:

- Analyzed requirements, identified function gap and derived project effort plan based on the business requirement.
- Turned the application performance by implementing database denormalization.
- Redesign backend demons to improve system performance and production stability.
- Core developer for a newly developed reporting system (POEM).

Technical Exposure: J2EE, Shell script, Tomcat, Apache, Oracle, Sybase, MQ, SSL, Linux, unix

Educational

Sep 2009 to Sep 2011

Oxford Brookes University

BSC in Computing and Information System

Sep 2004 to Sep 2006

Hong Kong Institute of Vocational Education

Higher Diploma in Systems Development & Administration

Sep 2003 to Sep 2004

Hong Kong Institute of Vocational Education

Higher Certificate in Information Systems management

Sep 1988 to May 1995

Ng Yuk Secondary School

Form 1 to Form 7 (Sci)

Professional Qualification

2019	Professional Scrum Master I
2018	AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Associate
2003	Sun Certified Programmer for the Java 2(1.4)

2000 MCSE NT4.0 (with SQL 7.0)

Language Spoken and Written

Spoken: Native in Cantonese; Fluent in English and Mandarin

Written: Proficient in English and Chinese.